Claire Falkenstein
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Personal and Business Records, 1936-1997, Series 3:; (Box 14-17, 41, 46-49; 4.2 linear feet)
  - Art Storage and Transport, 1951-1988 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Art Technique, circa 1940-1973 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1949-1951 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Artist Studio Tours, 1968-1986 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Arts and Activities Article, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Attorney Norman Ziff, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Bank Books, 1951-1954 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Bender Grants-in-Aid, Support Aids, 1942-1944 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Bender Grants-in-Aid, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Butterfield and Butterfield Actioneers, 1995-1997 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - California Art Review, 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - California Board of Equalization, 1969-1973 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - California Palace of the Legion of Honor, 1966-1968 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - California State University, Long Beach - Department of Art Advisory Council, 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Cedars-Sinai Medical Center - Advisory Council for the Arts (Marcia Weisman), circa 1976-1986 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Chapel of the Holy Cross, Arizona, circa 1966 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Clay Sculpture Formulas, circa 1936-1938 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Columbia Pictures TV, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Color, circa 1961, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Conservation - Falkenstein's Works, 1980, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Conservation Work, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Conservation - Works by Giacometti, 1975-1979 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Consignment Agreement with Armand Hammer Museum at UCLA, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Contracts, 1954-1984 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Contracts, 1968-1969, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Copyright, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Damage to Art Work in Storage, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Design, circa 1948-1958 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Designers West Article, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Design in Steel Award Program, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Directions for Handling the "Apple," 1973 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Documentary entitled "Claire Falkenstein, Sculptor," 1976-1980 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Donations of Art Work, circa 1968-1979 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Donations of Art Work, 1983-1993 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Donations of Art Work, circa 1980-1990 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Donation - Eureka College, 1968-1980 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Donation - Musee National d'art Moderne, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Downtown Los Angeles Art Center, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Peggie Dwight Inventory, circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Endorsements, 1972-1989 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Erotica, circa 1970 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Esthetics, circa 1950 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Eulogy of Grace Morley, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Experiments in Art and Technology, 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Experiments in Art and Technology, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Falkenstein Fountain on Long Beach Museum of Art Grounds, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Claire Falkenstein Research Project, 1995-1997 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Films, 1968-1972 (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Films, circa 1950-1984 (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - Film "Touching the Quick," 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - Film "Touching the Quick" - Artist Permission Letters and Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - Financial Agreements with Richard McCarthy, 1952, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - The Folk Tree, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 64)
  - Fresno Arts Center - Catalogue Reprint, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 65)
  - Gallery Records - Bolles Gallery, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 66)
  - Gallery Records - Comsky Gallery, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 67)
  - Gallery Records - Esther Robles Gallery, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 68)
  - Gallery Records - Gallery Mayer, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 69)
  - Gallery Records - Jack Rutberg Fine Arts Gallery, 1984-1991 (Box 14, Folder 70)
  - Gallery Records - Jack Rutberg Fine Arts Gallery, 1986-1995 (Box 14, Folder 71)
  - Gallery Records - Malvina Miller Gallery, 1971-1975 (Box 14, Folder 72)
  - Gallery Records - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1963-1966 (Box 14, Folder 73)
  - Gallery Records - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1967-1969 (Box 14, Folder 74)
  - Gallery Records - Martha Jackson Gallery, Sales, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 75)
  - Gallery Records - Polly Friedlander Gallery, 1973-1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Gallery Records - Torque Gallery, circa 1970-1982 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Gift to Hinkhouse Collection of Art at Stephens College, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Peggy Guggenheim, circa 1970-1980 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Haas Genealogy, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Harcourts Gallery, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - The Head-Royce School, 1994-1995 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Louis Heyn Will, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Hyman Hirsh Estate, 1961-1962 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Honor - The Women's Caucus for Art, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Incident with Gate Door at Ocean Front Walk Property, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Income Tax, 1959-1962, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Income Tax, 1982-1983 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Income Tax, 1986-1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Inheritance from Helen Bickel, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Insurance, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - International Design Conference, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - International Sculpture Competition, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Inventories of Art Work, circa 1964-1969 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Invitation, 1975, 1988-1993 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Invoices, circa 1950-1954 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Invoices - Paris, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Instituto Grafico Tiberino, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Jewelry Commissions, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Jewelry Design, circa 1950-1960 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Jewelry Orders, 1948-1985 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Jewelry Orders for Sculpture to Wear, Inc., 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - J.S. Guggenheim Fellowship - Application Material, 1946-1949, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 28-29)
  - J.S. Guggenheim Fellowship, 1949-1950 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - J.S. Guggenheim Fellowship, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - J.S. Guggenheim Fellowship, 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - J.S. Guggenheim Fellowship, 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 33-34)
  - J.S. Guggenheim Fellowship - Application with Photographs, 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 35-36)
  - Juried Shows, 1949-1970 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Juried Shows, 1968, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Juried Shows, 1973-1991 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Juried Show - Art in Public Spaces, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Juror - Albert Bender Grant, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Juror - California Resources Council, Pacifica Awards, 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Juror - California State Fair Art Show, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Juror - Fresno Arts Center and Museum, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Juror - Long Beach Art Association, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Juror - Long Beach Art Association - 3D Exhibition, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Juror - Olympic Architecture Competition, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Juror - San Diego Art Institute, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 48-49)
  - Juror - Westwood Center of the Arts, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Juror - Writers Guild of America, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - La Quinta Arts Festival, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Lawsuit about Roof Installation, 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Learning French, circa 1947-1958, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Lease for Great Jones Street in New York, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lecture - California Arts Project Summer Institute, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Lectures - Invitation Thank-you Notes, 1973-1985 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Legal Issues, 1957, 1969, 1979-1982 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The Light Bringer Project, 1988, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Lists of "Things To Do," circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Listing Contract for Victoria Avenue Property, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Falkenstein Living-Trust Transfer Deed, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Loans of Art Work, 1982, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Loans of Art Work, 1990-1995 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Loan - Oakland Museum, 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Long Beach Museum of Art, 1968, 1990-1993 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Los Angeles Museum of Art - Purchase of "Struttura Grafica," 1973 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Mailing Lists, 1949-1969 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Mailing Lists, circa 1970-1990 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Memberships, 1936-1937 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Florence Minard, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Organizations, 1949-1950, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 20-21)
  - Grace Morley, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Mortgage for Venice Property, 1987-1989 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Murals, circa 1948-1950 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Musee des Arts Decoratifs, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Musee De L'Homme, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), 1974 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - National Museum of Women in the Arts, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - National Museum of Women in the Arts, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - New York Studio, 1959-1963 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Ocean Front Property, 1963-1967 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Ocean Front Property - Purchase, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Ocean Front Property - Renovation, circa 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Ocean Front Property - Renovation, 1987-1990, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 34-35)
  - May O'Donnell and Ray Green, 1950-1983 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Paris, circa 1950-1960 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Paris, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Paris Expenses, 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Paris Sculpture "Couple," 1985 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Paris Studio, circa 1954-1969 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Paris Studio, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Paris Studio, 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Paris Studio, 1984-1985 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Paris Studio, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Paris Studio, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Paris Studio, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Paris Studio, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Patents, 1944-1976 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Pablo Picasso, circa 1940-1970 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Giacomo Patri, circa 1966-1978 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Patri School of Art Fundamentals, circa 1953 (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - Pepsi-Cola Fellowship in Painting, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Petroglyphs, circa 1945 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Phoenix Art Museum, 1967-1979 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Poetry - Jim Sudalnik, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Poetry - Richard Moore, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Pond Farm History, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - Price Lists, circa 1941-1990, (4 folders) (Box 16, Folder 59-62)
  - Property on Pleasant Street, San Francisco, circa 1940 (Box 16, Folder 63)
  - Property on Water Street, San Francisco, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 64)
  - Purchase of Ocean Front Property, circa 1966-1971 (Box 16, Folder 65)
  - Herbert Read's Manuscript, circa 1991 (Box 16, Folder 66)
  - Recipes, circa 1970 (Box 16, Folder 67)
  - Recommendations, 1973, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 68-69)
  - Reconditioning of "Accelerating Point" for San Diego Museum of Art, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 70)
  - Patricia Renick, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 71)
  - Rodia's Towers in Watts, 1958-1969 (Box 16, Folder 72)
  - Sale of Art Work, 1952-1962 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Sale of Art Work, circa 1955-1996 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Sale of Art Work, 1969-1984, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
  - Sale of Mark Tobey Abstract, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Sale of Art Work - Phoenix Art Museum, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - San Francisco Landscape Garden Show, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art - Artists' Cookbook, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - San Francisco Society of Women Artists - Bulletins, 1931-1942 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - San Francisco Society of Women Artists, 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - San Francisco Society of Women Artists - Bylaws and Constitution, circa 1946-1954 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco State University, Distinguished Artists Forum, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - The Santiago Collection, 1981-1984 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Bozidar von Serda, 1964-1968 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Slide Lists of Art Work, 1976-1994 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Slide Lists for Galleries and Collectors, 1977-1984 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Rena Small - Artists' Hands, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Sotheby's Sale, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Steel, circa 1963 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Storage, circa 1950-1976 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Studio and Storage Expenses, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Studio Tours, 1970-1983, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Suggested Titles for Art Work, circa 1990 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, Inc., 1969-1971 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Michel Tapie, circa 1951-1973 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Michel Tapie, circa 1953-1965, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 26-27)
  - Tenure for Garner Tullis, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Third International Congress of Art Critics, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Mark Tobey, circa 1990 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Mark Tobey - Exhibition Material, 1954, 1959-1960, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Tom Mooney Labor Movement, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Tools, circa 1959-1962 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Trip to New York, 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Trip to Europe, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Trip to Berlin, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Trip to Barcelona and Italy, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Trips to Italy, 1960-1963 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Trip to Paris, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Trip to India, Hawaii, and Western Europe, 1969-1971, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 40-41)
  - Trip to New York, Venice, and Paris, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Trip to New York and Paris, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Trip to Japan, circa 1975 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Tour - Art Today in France, 1958-1959 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Tour - Art Today in France, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Tour - Art Today in Italy, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Tour - Art Today in Italy, Notes About Trip, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Tour - Art Today in Italy, Report, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Tour - Art Today in France and Italy, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Typography, circa 1940-1970, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 51-52)
  - UCLA, Frederick S. Wright Art Gallery, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - UCLA Oral History Program - Colloqium, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - UNESCO, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Use of Falkenstein's Art in Publications, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Venice, California, 1967-1973 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Victoria Avenue Property, 1976-1986 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Visiting Artist at California State Polytechnic University, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Weisman Museum of Art, Pepperdine University, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Welding, Color, and Plastics, circa 1966-1977 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Western Roundtable of Modern Art, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - Franz Wildenhain, circa 1950-1960 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Women's Work - American Art '74, Phildelphia Civic Center, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - Women's Caucus for Art, 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - Women's Caucus for Art, 1994-1995 (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - Women's Caucus for Art, Award for Outstanding Achievement in the Visual Arts, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Work Logs, 1976-1978, (3 folders) (Box 17, Folder 68-70)
  - Work Opportunities, 1961-1985 (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - Work Plan, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 72)
  - Oversized Studio Visitors' Logs, circa 1964-1995 (Box 41)
  - Expense Journals, 1964-1969 (Box 46)
  - Expense Journals, 1970-1974 (Box 47)
  - Expense Journals, 1975-1979 (Box 48)
  - Expense Journals, 1980-1985, 1990 (Box 49)
- Exhibitions, 1930-1996, Series 4:; (Box 18-21, 42, OV 50; 3.3 linear feet)
  Falkenstein maintained comprehensive documentation of her exhibitions from her first exhibition in the 1930s to the last one at the Merging One Gallery in 1996. Files include both a chronological record and individual record for nearly all of her exhibitions. Found with the files are correspondence, photographs, loan and shipping records, catalogs, announcements, clippings, articles, and other records.
  The files for exhibitions at the Fresno Art Museum, Martha Jackson Gallery and Jack Rutberg Fine Art Gallery are particularly rich and often personal. Correspondence within the files is particularly interesting as it often provides her own and sometimes her friends' reviews.
  The files are arranged first by general exhibitions in chronological order and then alphabetically by individual exhibition. There is some duplication between the two groups of files. Within each folder, contents are arranged chronologically by date. Most of the photographs related to exhibitions are found in the Photographs Series.
  - General Exhibitions, 1930-1953, (32 folders) (Box 18, Folder 1-32)
  - General Exhibitions, 1954-1978, (33 folders) (Box 19, Folder 1-33)
  - General Exhibitions, 1979-1995, (18 folders) (Box 20, Folder 1-18)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, Society for Contemporary Art, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Arts Council Cultural Center, Thousand Oaks, CA, 1974-1976 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Artists for Victory Exhibit at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Berkeley Art Museum, circa 1935 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Blue Cross of Southern California, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Bolles Gallery, San Francisco, 1958-1959 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - California Museum of Science and Industry, 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Coos Art Museum, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art - "Still Working," 1994 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Craft and Folk Art Museum, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Crocker Art Museum, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Denise Cade Gallery, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Design Center of Los Angeles - Broad Spectrum: Contemporary Los Angeles Painters and Sculptors, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Fisher Gallery - "Take 2," 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Fresno Arts Center, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 34-35)
  - Fresno Arts Center and Museum, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Fresno Art Museum, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Fresno Art Museum, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Grossmont College Art Gallery, 1977, (Oversized item housed in Box 42) (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Jack Rutberg Fine Arts Gallery, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Jack Rutberg Fine Arts Gallery, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Long Beach Museum, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Los Angeles and Seoul Contemporary Arts (LASCA), 1995 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Loyola Marymount University, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1972, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Marin County Art and Garden Center, Garden Sculpture Show, 1947, (Oversized item housed in OV 50) (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Matrix Workshop of Women Artists - "Sculpture Sacramento," 1982 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - Merging One Gallery, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Michael Dunev Gallery - "The Ties That Bind," 1988 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Muckenthaler Cultural Center, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - National Museum of Women in the Arts - "Generation of Mentors," 1994 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Palm Springs Desert Museum, Retrospective Exhibition, 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 53-54)
  - Parson School of Design - "Still Working," 1993 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - Phoenix Art Museum, 1967-1968 (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - Roberts Art Gallery, Santa Monica High School, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - Rutgers University Art Gallery, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 58)
  - The San Francisco Landscape Garden Show, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 59)
  - San Francisco State University, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 60)
  - Santa Monica College Art Museum - "The Peace Show," 1982 (Box 20, Folder 61)
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, 1974-1976 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1946-1947 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Sepulveda Junior High School, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Sherman Foundation Center, Corona del Mar, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Torque Galleries, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
  - Utah State University, Nora Eccles Harrison Art Museum, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - University of California, Riverside - "The Continuing Vision of Claire Falkenstein," 1984 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Van Straatan Gallery, 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Victoria and Albert Museum, London, 1960-1961 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Walker Art Center - "Modern Jewelry Under Fifty Dollars," 1948 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Wight Art Gallery, UCLA, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Falkenstein's Studio - "Los Angeles is on Fire," circa 1980 (Box 42)
  - Oversized Grossmont College Art Gallery - "Topological Investigations," 1977, (from Box. 20, F. 39) (Box 42)
  - Oversized Marin County Art and Garden Center, Garden Sculpture Show, - Drawing, 1947, (from Box 20, F. 46) (Box OV 50)
  - Oversized San Francisco Museum of Modern Art - Sketch Detail of Exhibit, 1948 (Box OV 50)
- Commissions, 1930-1992, Series 5:; (Box 21-22, OV 50-54; 2 linear feet)
  Commission files document nearly all of Falkenstein's public and private large-scale projects and often contain a visual record of the work, as well as correspondence, design notes, contracts, and expense reports. The files are arranged by general commission files, followed by individual projects, both public and private. The general commission files contain documentation on requests for commission work that was not completed, commission submissions that were not accepted, and publicity material.
  Individual commission project files provide rich documentation on Falkenstein's many commissioned art works, with particular emphasis on the World War II murals; Peggy Guggenheim gates in Venice; the screens, windows and doors at St. Basils Church in Los Angeles; the fountain at California Federal Savings and Loan; and sculptures at California State University, University of California, Los Angeles, and the University of Southern California. These detailed files include correspondence, contracts, expense estimates and reports, invoices, designs, sketches, and photographs.
  The bulk of the photographs of commissions are found in the Photograph series. Also, most of Falkenstein's jewelry design commissions are found in the Personal and Business Records series. Additional correspondence and other materials related to commissions are found in the Correspondence series and Personal and Business Records.
  The files are arranged first by general commissions in chronological order and then alphabetically by individual commissions. Within each folder, contents are arranged chronologically by date.
  - General Commissions, 1930, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - General Commissions, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - General Commissions, 1960-1964 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - General Commissions, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - General Commissions, 1973-1976, (3 folders) (Box 21, Folder 17-19)
  - Airport Commission Submissions, 1976, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - M. J. Aldadeff Necklace, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Leon Banks - Entrance Screen, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - California Center in San Francisco, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - California Department of Motor Vehicles - "Interchange-Traffic," 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - California Federal Savings and Loan, Los Angeles - "Structure and Flow #2," circa 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - California Federal Savings and Loan, Los Angeles - "Structure and Flow #2" Controversy about Water, circa 1967-1978 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - California Federal Savings and Loan, Los Angeles - "Structure and Flow #2" Documentation on Destruction, 1989-1991 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - California Senate Offices, Washington - California Art for California Senators Program, 1973-1975 (Box 21, Folder 28)